Hello English learners and welcome
back to English Pod. My name is Marco.
And my name is Catherine and
it's the Christmas season Marco.
So that means we have a
very festive lesson today.
That's right. Christmas is
coming up and well, a tradition
among many people around the
world is to buy a Christmas tree.
That's right. I remember
when we used to do this in my
family, it was one of my
favorite times of the year.
So we're going to explore this in today's
lesson. After we listen to the dialogue,
we'll be back to talk about some of
these interesting words and phrases.
I'm home. Everyone come here.
I bought a Christmas tree.
Look at this beautiful pine tree.
Wow, it's huge.
Are you sure it will
fit in the living room?
Awesome. I'll go get
the Christmas lights.
Of course it will. Help me
put it in the living room.
I found the lights. I got
the Christmas or whatever.
We could also place these
stockings next to the chimney.
Great idea. While we
decorate the tree, we
can listen to some good
old Christmas songs.
All right, we're back
and as we mentioned,
the entire dialogue is
about a Christmas tree.
So why don't you explain
what a Christmas tree is?
Because many people maybe
don't even do or buy Christmas trees.
Okay, well, Christmas
tree is usually a green
tree that we cut down
and we put in the house.
Okay, so it's not a real tree
with roots in the ground,
but sometimes it comes
from a real tree outside.
And the tree is very small
on the top and it goes
out like a triangle. Okay,
so it's a special shape.
And we generally make it look very pretty
with lights and ornaments and decorations.
And on Christmas, on the 25th or the
24th, it depends where you come from.
We put lots of presents
underneath the Christmas tree.
Wow, it sounds amazing.
Well, yeah, and it looks very nice.
It does look really beautiful and it's
just a really special part of Christmas.
And well, as you mentioned, sometimes
the tree is just a fake plastic tree, but
many times it's a real tree and the
type of tree that you use is a pine tree.
Exactly. And so pine tree is a kind of tree
that doesn't have leaves. It has needles.
That means that there are long, very thin
green pieces that are all over the tree.
And you can see these trees in
most northern places like Scandinavia
or in America, maybe Illinois and
Minnesota and Michigan and Vermont.
And they're very, as you
say, very unique trees, but
they also have a very special
smell, the smell of pine.
They do. It's such a nice smell that a
lot of the things that we use in America
to clean our houses have a pine smell
because it makes the house smell nice.
Very good. So a pine tree. The dad
brought a pine tree or a Christmas
tree home and well, the wife
was a little bit worried if it will fit.
Okay, will it fit? This is a
very important question
because a lot of pine
trees are very, very tall.
So if a pine tree is three meters tall
or four meters tall, will it fit? Is the
question we ask, is it too big or is it going
to be stuck on the ceiling in the house?
And so we could ask this about anything.
I just bought a new TV.
Will it fit in the living
room? I don't know.
I'm very nervous. I
spent a lot of money.
All right. And well, you were
talking about the Christmas
tree and how you put a
lot of nice decorations on it.
And so we say that we decorate the tree.
That's right. So the verb here,
this is an action word to decorate.
So every holiday season in my family,
we take one day and we decorate the tree.
That means that we take very
small special ornaments and ribbons
and lights and we put them on
the tree to make the tree look pretty.
Wow.
You can also say decorate the house
or to decorate the house for a party.
So this means to make something
look special or pretty. Very good.
Um, we've taken a look at very specific
words related to, you know, Christmas
trees and decorating it. So why
don't we listen to the dialogue again?
And we'll be back to continue
with some more language takeaway.
I'm home. Everyone come here.
I bought a Christmas tree.
Look at this beautiful pine tree.
Wow. It's huge. Are you sure
it will fit in the living room?
Awesome. I'll go get the Christmas lights.
Of course it will help me
put it in the living room.
I found the lights.
I got the Christmas ornaments.
We could also place these
stockings next to the chimney.
Great idea. While we
decorate the tree, we
can listen to some good
old Christmas songs.
All right. We're back. So
why don't we take a look
at three more words on
language takeaway part two.
There's just so many words that are
associated with Christmas and the Christmas
season that we have to look at them
again here in language takeaway part two.
And the first one we've
already mentioned, it goes
together with the phrase
to decorate the tree.
Okay. So what do we decorate the tree
with Marco? You mentioned ornaments.
That's right. Christmas ornaments.
Christmas ornaments.
And so an ornament is
a thing. It's something
that we use to make
something else look prettier.
And so in this case, ornaments are
sometimes round and red or green or gold.
We hang them on the tree.
And well, this is in this case, it's a
Christmas ornament for the tree.
But an ornament can be
anything any nice piece of art
or something they can use
to decorate your house, right?
Exactly. And in my family ornaments
aren't just those round circles or
balls for Christmas, every family
member has a special kind of ornament.
So my dad has Santa Claus
ornaments and my mom has
bunny rabbit ornaments
and I have angel ornaments.
So everybody has a special one.
Oh, that's really nice.
And well, apart from ornaments, there is
also this tradition of hanging stockings.
Okay, so a stocking you might
have heard this word before
in the sense of a clothing
item, a stocking is like a sock.
A big sock.
And it also means old, old stockings
that women would wear, like tights.
But in this case, a stocking,
a Christmas stocking
is a very, very, very
big sock that we hang.
And on Christmas, we get to fill it with
very special things like candy and toys.
Very good. So actually you hang
the stockings and the common
place to do it in, or to put
them on, is on the chimney, right?
That's right. So there's a
fireplace. And usually above
the fireplace, there's a
shelf. We call it a mantle.
And there's a place there to
hang these. And the place where
all of the smoke from the
fire comes out is the chimney.
It's also the place where
Santa Claus comes down.
Right. So you have the fireplace
where you put the wood, you have
the mantle, that's the space where
you actually put the stockings on.
And the tube that goes up and where the
smoke comes out of is called the chimney.
Right. So you don't want to live
there. And then actually the joke
is that Santa Claus is definitely
too fat to go down the chimney.
But it's a special place in the Christmas
story because that's what Santa Claus does.
Very good. Interesting words. Why don't
we listen to this dialogue one last time?
I'm home. Everyone come here.
I bought a Christmas tree.
Look at this beautiful pine tree.
Wow. It's huge. Are you sure
it will fit in the living room?
Awesome. I'll go get
the Christmas lights.
Of course it will. Help me
put it in the living room.
I found the lights. I got
the Christmas elements.
We could also place these
stockings next to the chimney.
Great idea. While we
decorate the tree, we
can listen to some good
old Christmas songs.
Alright. We're back. So as you say,
the Christmas season is important in
America and people not only decorate
Christmas trees, but also their house.
And even outside, they put
Christmas lights all over the house.
They put little statues of
Santa Claus and reindeer.
And it's a very, I don't know,
sometimes, lavish thing to do.
It is. It's almost funny how
much people like to spend on,
not just time, but also money
on decorating their houses.
And so where I come from,
people decorate the outsides a lot.
You have Christmas lights
on all parts of the house.
And then maybe, you know, all of the
reindeer in the front yard, all whatever,
then the other, they're like 12 of
them or nine of them, I don't remember.
It's 12. But actually, it was nice because when I lived there, with my parents,
we would go out and tour around the neighborhood just to see other people's
Christmas lights and decorations because, as we say, some of them can be
very, very nice and they take a lot of time and effort into decorating it.
They do. It's really special. And
at my house, we generally just
decorated the inside. But sometimes
we did lights on the outside.
And there's some very
funny movies to talk about
this like National Lampoon's
Christmas Vacation.
Right.
And so there's some really funny scenes
about putting Christmas lights on the house.
All right. Well, that's all the
time we have for today, but we'll
definitely post a link of this
movie that's actually very good.
It kind of depicts the traditional
American in a funny way.
It's a very funny movie.
All right. And if you have any
questions, any other doubts or
comments, you can come to
EnglishPod.com and we'll see you there.
We will. So enjoy the Christmas
season and until next time, guys. Bye.